Ayomide Ibosiola

Technical Recruiter || Software Developer

Ikeja, Lagos 100271 enochibosiola@gmail.com 08099691225

I am a Technical Recruiter with a strong Software Development background; specialized in building web applications that are aesthetically pleasing and logic driven.

There's nothing like the thrill of a candidate's enthusiastic "Yes!" to an offer, and an equally pleased Hiring Manager who just landed a top performer. Perhaps even more satisfying is successfully recruiting a superstar and then seeing him/her develop a billion-dollar product. Knowing my efforts impact the bottom line keeps me going every day.

In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements. This has allowed me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver exceptional works to all of my clients.

Work Experience

Frontend Developer || Technical Recruiter

Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd - Bengaluru, Karnataka September 2021 to March 2022

Pericius Pvt Ltd are leaders in emergent technology and consulting in diverse industries. We continually work with clients across all sectors turning their insightful information to meet business requirements across Blockchain, Business Process Automation, Product Design, Consultation, Identity Management, Digital Assets, Digital Financial Suite, and Fintech Service Provider.

- Create new features, functionality and capabilities, specifically in the Contract Management System using ReactJS, Ant Design, Material UI and Java.
- Perform bug fixes and code reviews.
- Recommend solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the design team.
- Pinpoint candidate motivators and used them to successfully recruit quality candidates.
- Analyze job descriptions and communicated with the Hiring Manager (Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd) to clarify terms that could be vague; earned job-satisfaction rates of 95 percent from candidate/company matches as a result of this attention to detail.

Technical Copywriter

Marketpath Inc

August 2021 to November 2021

Marketpath, Inc. is a leading provider of web design, development and on-demand Web Content Management Solutions that allow for fast and easy management of websites for non-technical and technical users.

• Gathered and analyzed technical and product information from various sources to document new or

changing product functionality.

• Developed product manuals, how-to guides, website help sections, journal articles, and other content that distills technical information with ease and clarity.

Frontend Developer

Ikoyi - Lagos

May 2021 to June 2021

Mezovest is the best and easiest way to access loans online with no collateral. Mezovest enables businesses from mom and pop shops to global conglomerates - receives loans easier, faster and safer at lowest interest rate.

• Built an online payment gateway that allows businesses make and receive payments across continents, currencies, preferred payment methods, and platforms.

Software Developer

Royal Crystal Airways - Lagos October 2020 to January 2021

Royal Crystal Airways Ltd is an international airways company flying across many destinations from Lagos, Nigeria to wherever in the Gulf, Europe, Asia, Africa, and North America.

- Built the Web Application for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip using ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Stylus and ES6.
- Oversaw the outsourced Mobile Application development for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip.

Frontend Developer

Midra Solutions - Lagos January 2019 to March 2020

Midra Solutions is a service delivery company that provides a combination of technology and media services. Our core competency, developed through extensive worldwide exposure to a variety of business processes, industries, and Technologies. Our strength lies in providing client focused Business Consulting and Re- Engineering of IT Services.

- Maintained, optimized, troubleshot, and improved websites.
- Created standardized websites and mobile responsive applications using mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Implemented applications and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Built reusable code for future use.

Software Developer (Intern)

Lagosbuild - Ogba, Lagos January 2017 to January 2019

LAGOSBUILD is a platform to train Africans how to code, specifaclly Machine Learning, UX Design and Web Development.

- Standardized website output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.

• Integrated data from varios back-end services and databases.

Education

Undergraduate in Microbiology

Obafemi Awolowo University

February 2015 to August 2019

Skills

- · Discretion and decision making
- Communications
- Ability to develop strong relationships and connections
- Vanilla JavaScript
- Material UI
- Ant Design
- VueJS
- ReactJS
- · Proficiency with Microsoft Office
- ATS Software

Certifications and Licenses

Tech Recruitment Certified Professional - DevSkiller

March 2022 to Present

Tech Recruitment Certification issued by DevSkiller is a IT Recruitment course for everyone and designed with recruiting professionals, HR Managers, sourcers and entrepreneurs in mind.

Tech Recruitment Certification helps you stay on top of the latest trends in the IT recruitment world.

ReactJS for Beginners - Simplilearn

January 2022 to Present

JavaScript for Beginners - Simplilearn

January 2022 to Present

Getting Started with ReactJS Components - Simplifearn

December 2021

Soft Skills Course - Jobberman Nigeria

April 2021 to Present

Certificate of Language Ability - Emmersion

March 2021 to Present

HTML/CSS and JavaScript - TestDome

March 2021 to Present